we have special guests with us right now
so we're gonna talk about all the stuff
that's happening with The Whistleblower
and Donald Trump and the Ukraine and Joe
Biden and hunter Biden and we're not
even gonna talk about the creepy stuff
about hundred bite him now you're gonna
bring it up so we're just gonna talk
about this corruption stuff we have our
special guest with us he is friend of
the show he's a columnist for reader
supported news and he co-hosts the show
loud and clear on Sputnik radio he was
also a CIA operations officer until he
what he blew the whistle on the CIA for
its use of waterboarding please welcome
back to the show John Kiriakou hey John
how are you
so no John you're a whistleblower so
that means the press protected you and a
lot of people in Congress stood up for
you and they let you remain anonymous
right see because I couldn't blow the
whistle on the CIA's torture program
through proper channels because my
proper channels created the torture
program and I couldn't go even around my
proper channels to the oversight
committees because the oversight
committees funded the torture program
and then covered it up so I elected to
go to the media which resulted in the
the entire weight of the US government
falling on my head but that's okay it
was it was an experience that in the end
was worth it so wait a minute you are a
whistleblower and you ended up being
prosecuted by the same government that
you were blowing the whistle on yeah and
the funny thing about that Jimmy is is
that I was I was investigated initially
by the Bush administration because I had
blown the whistle during the George W
Bush administration and and then in
December of 2008 the Bush Justice
Department found ruled decided whatever
you want to say that I had not committed
a crime and they sent my lawyers
something called a declination letter
declining to prosecute me for weeks
later when Barack Obama became president
and John Brennan became the deputy
national security council John being an
old nemesis of mine from the CIA John
asked the
this department to secretly reopen the
case against me and so for the next
three years I had no idea that my phones
were tapped that my emails were being
intercepted and that I had three
different groups of FBI agents
surveilling me 24 hours a day finally in
January of 2012 I was arrested by the
FBI and charged with five felonies
including three counts of espionage
coming out of my whistleblowing in the
end of course I hadn't committed
espionage that's a that's a tactic that
they use to try to coerce you into
pleading guilty and they were successful
once I went bankrupt they dropped all
the espionage charges and I took a plea
to a lesser charge but I ended up going
to prison for 23 months Wow that's well
that's what's because you see a lot of
people saying stuff about Edward Snowden
or Chelsea Manning or then oh they
didn't they didn't go through the proper
channels and of course you just
elucidate why going through the proper
channels is often not an open track for
you to do that because those channels
are the very people you're blowing the
whistle on and actually because that's a
very important point and I really want
people to understand this I have a
friend Tom Drake who's a major whistle
blower at NSA so Tom Drake stumbled in
the in the immediate aftermath of the
9/11 attacks Tom Drake stumbled on
information showing that NSA was was
targeting American citizens this blanket
surveillance warrantless wiretapping
interception of emails and phone calls
of American citizens clearly illegal so
he went through the chain of command he
went first to his boss and was told to
mind his own business then he went to
the Inspector General just like this new
CI a whistleblower did the Inspector
General didn't know what the heck he was
talking about because it wasn't read
into the compartment then he went to the
general counsel was told to just beg off
then he went to the Pentagon inspector
general because NSA is a DoD agency the
Pentagon inspector general actually
destroyed the evidence that
brought out with him so then Tom went to
the Oversight Committee the house
permanent Select Committee on
Intelligence and he ended up getting
nine felony charges including seven
counts of espionage for doing exactly as
he was taught to do to go through the
chain of command so the chain of
commands a joke the chain of command
actually it's a bad joke it doesn't work
you are gonna lose your career you're
probably gonna lose your money and you
might lose your freedom even if you go
through the chain of command alright so
there you go so that's it's amazing how
the whistleblower when it comes to Trump
is a hero but the whistleblower when it
came to George Bush and Barack Obama are
the worst guys in the world meaning
Chelsea Manning you and Julian Assange
and it's not--and Edward Snowden and
that's the way it is which is which is
funny and sad at the same time because
we have a federal whistleblower law in
this country and we have a new law
that's that's supposed to protect
whistleblowers in the intelligence
community and and it's a joke you know
if you if you blow the whistle on let's
say money laundering or tax evasion or
bank fraud like Brad Birkenfeld did at
UBS Brad Birkenfeld although he was
prosecuted too wrongly I believe and
went to prison for three and a half
years when he got out he got a 104
million dollar settlement from the
Treasury Department for his
whistleblowing but if you're in national
security forget it you're going to
prison and you're going a real prison
not some minimum security work camp you
didn't get a settlement man I am still
digging my way out of bankruptcy it's
awful well listen I'm glad you here
because we have a another whistleblower
inside the White House John this is
great news someone's gonna tell the
truth and it seems like all the
politicians learned from your case
because now they're protecting the
whistleblower well here it is New York
Times revealed that the whistleblower
who was blew the whistle on Trump
pressuring the Ukraine government to get
dirt on his political opponent meaning
Joe Biden the whistleblower was from the
CIA and he was detailed
inside the White House so this is right
for the New York Times it says the
Wizard blower who revealed that
President Trump sought foreign help for
his reelection and that the White House
sought to cover it up is a CIA officer
who was detailed to work at the White
House at one point according to three
people familiar with his identity
the man has since returned to the CIA
the people said little little else is
known about him now let me just let me
just stop here is that normal John for a
CIA guy to be working kind of inside the
seat inside the White House kind of
against the people in the White House
you know I mean kind of spying on them
is that normal though is that there are
a whole bunch of jobs at the National
Security Council that are reserved for
CIA analysts so if you're a really great
analyst and you get up to the GS 14 or
gs-15 level your reward rather than to
be transferred somewhere else around the
building your reward is to go down to
the White House for a year and if you're
really good you can extend that for a
second year and then when you go back to
CIA headquarters you get promoted so
everybody wants to do a one or two year
rotation at the White House this tells
me that this guy is legit that he was a
top analyst that he was rewarded for his
analysis by being sent to the White
House for a year or two he saw something
that scared the daylights out of him and
then he went back to the CIA now one of
the interesting things that I noticed in
this New York's New York Times piece was
his understanding and familiarity with
the so called transcript of this call
first of all that was not a transcript
that was what's called a mem con a
Memorandum of conversation or a telecon
mem Telkom Memorandum of a telephone
conversation those are generally not
circulated to the analysts at the CIA
they are internal NSC documents and so
it tells me that he was probably still
at an at the NSC when he read the
document and only very recently
went back to the CIA and then reported
what he had learned through CIA channels
so I think this guy's probably a top
analyst so you don't think that the CIA
I mean what is your so the view of this
show and us here as far as Russia gate
goes is that that was drummed up by the
mostly the intelligence community to
mess with Trump and so this too well for
it well this let me give you the rest of
the and then it'll come back to you
because so the man has returned to the
CIA the people said little else is known
about this guy and according I love with
my friend Katelyn Johnson said this she
says so there you have it a mysterious
stranger from the lying torturing
propagandizing drug trafficking
assassinating coup staging war mongering
psychopathic CIA was working in the
White House heroically provided the
political media class with politically
powerful information out of the goodness
of his heart
and then vanished off into the Langley
sunset clearly there's nothing
suspicious about this at all she goes on
to say in all seriousness even the call
this spook a whistleblower is ridiculous
on its face you don't get to call
someone from the US intelligence
community a whistleblower unless they're
actually whistleblowing on the US
intelligence community that's that's not
a thing unless you did it like you did
John Hitz she says the CIA liberally
leaks information wherever it's
convenient for CIA agendas while
withholding all other information behind
a veil of government secrecy a CIA
officer who exposes information about
CIA wrongdoings without the CIA's
permission is a whistleblower which is
what John Kiriakou is a CIA officer who
exposes information about someone else
is just a spook doing spook things you
can recognize the latter by the way the
mass media supports and applause it
employs them like they're now paid
consultants the former head of the CIA
hunts for MSNBC and CNN and you can
recognize the former the real deal
whistleblowers by the way they have been
persecuted imprisoned and/or died under
mysterious circumstances and that would
be also you so do you have any wood how
do you reset it i my my
detector goes off when they say it's a
whistleblower who works for the CIA if
they after they just got done blowing
their russia gate scam that they tried
to pull entre and this goes back to wet
i'll go ahead let me i'll go back to so
go ahead i just want to give you
responsible anymore
i think she's absolutely right I'll tell
you what I'd like to ask this
whistleblower is Ukraine aside I want to
know about the drone program I want to
know if there's still a torture program
that's been reconstituted I want to know
about secret renditions I want to know
about secret prisons do we still have
them if so where are they we don't know
any of that stuff so I have to agree
with with Caitlin Johnstone this this
guy this guy wants the best of both
worlds
he wants to be seen as a whistleblower
and by God the mainstream media has
bestowed that upon him and he wants to
take down Donald Trump and he wants to
just ride off into the sunset maybe get
another promotion for having done what
he's done but let me add one more thing
to Jimmy it took my attorneys especially
jesselyn Radack one year and I mean
working full-time for one year to get
the mainstream media specifically
CNN and MSNBC to stop calling me
CIA leaker John Kiriakou and to start
calling me CIA whistleblower John
Kiriakou finally the week before I went
to prison a year after my arrest
CIA caught I'm sorry CNN called me a
whistleblower MSNBC called me a
whistleblower with quotation marks
around the word whistleblower and then
Rachel Maddow who's supposed to be this
great chapter always every time she says
my name she always says John Kiriakou
who styles himself a whistleblower
uh-huh and then she can't understand why
I won't go on her show yeah she's the
worst you should go on her show and say
she styles herself a journalist yes you
can have that John so this is quite a
tweet so Caitlyn then tweeted this and I
want to show everybody this because it
really breaks it down she says take off
the revolutionaries mask and it's the
CIA that's Juan Guido take off the
terrorists mask and it's the CIA that's
al-qaeda we've funded them we also
through Saudi Arabia take off the
newsman's mask and it's the CIA well you
know I we already showed you that on the
show take off the filmmakers mask and
it's the CIA that's the white helmets
take off the whistleblowers mask and
it's the CIA yeah she's
absolutely right she's absolutely right
and what kind of bizarro world do we
live in where now all of a sudden
practically overnight it's the CIA
that's the good guys what that right
that that's like movies I can't so here
I want to play this for everybody you've
seen this I'm and everybody who watches
the show seen it but it bears repeating
so here is Chuck Schumer talking with
the venerated / Richelieu Stiles herself
as a journalist Rachel Maddow who's a
propagandist of the highest order
thirty thousand dollars a day to post a
she pulls anyway here is Chuck
Schumer they're admitting this is what's
called a gaffe and a gaffe is when you
accidentally tell the truth and that's
what he's doing here he's actually gonna
let the cat out of the bag about what
the CIA does if you don't go along with
them even if you're the President of the
United States he's taking these you take
on the intelligence community they have
six ways from Sunday is getting back at
you so even for a practical supposedly
hard-nosed businessman who's being
really dumb to do this what do you think
the intelligence community would do if
they were mine I don't know what I from
what I am told they are very upset with
how he has treated them and talked about
them and so John to me this is
exactly what Chuck Schumer predicted the
CIA then went in messed with Donald
Trump with the steel dossier which was
completely debunked they went and bet
was basically Russia gate they got that
the FISA warrant on him in such a BS
manner and then they still couldn't
prove their goddamn case there they did
it all under there's so much corruption
around Trump yet they did it under the
one thing he didn't do which was collude
with Russia in the twenty-sixth
collected so they failed at that and now
they're gonna try to do this Ukraine
thing which is why that's why it's what
it looks like to me which is why I
wanted to bring you on does that what it
looks like to you this again the CIA is
messin with the president even though he
may have done something corrupt it's
still them trying to get him right
absolutely yes you know when when Chuck
Schumer gave that interview the very
next day I was invited on to CNN to to
explain what his comments meant were
they talking about November 22nd 1963
was one of the questions and I said no
they're not talking about November 22nd
1963 what they're talking about and this
is where I made a mistake Jimmy I
underestimated them and their malice I
said what they're talking about is they
can make this president fail they can
make him fail by slow-rolling him if
they don't like a president they know
that they can outweigh him because these
guys at the senior levels of the CIA
have been there for 20 30 35 years I
knew one guy at the CIA who was who was
in the senior intelligence service
leadership for 42 years so they know
that presidents come and go and they're
always going to be there what they do
then is if the president says oh I want
you to focus on China they say yeah yeah
we're gonna get right on that
and they just ignore him because they in
four years he's gonna be gone and
somebody else is gonna be president what
I didn't think was that they had the
guts to actively take up measures
against a president and now I've got to
agree with you I think we've seen them
do it twice
we saw them do it with with Russia gate
knowing that that was bogus information
and then they continue to leak bogus
information
through their Stooges like Kendall a
nyan at NBC and MSNBC too to pollute the
the media with this nonsensical
storyline it failed when the Muller
report came out and now I think we're
seeing him do it again yeah it was a big
crash in Bern especially if you watched
the Moller testimony I mean not watch
the news media's coverage of it but if
you actually watch the bonus that's the
mone it was it was a case of Elder Abuse
and they would say was sad it was worse
than it was worse than watching Joe
Biden try to tell you to keep a record
player on it sure and that was the face
of warranty been against Carter page you
know that word was was falsely obtained
yes and it was falsely renewed and
everybody just seems to have been
they've forgotten about it
there there should be there should be a
Justice Department investigation on the
CIA officers or whoever did it the FBI
agents who went to the FISA Court and
swore that the information they had was
true and used that false information to
get these fights and warrants on Carter
page they Oh Carter page an apology and
somebody needs to be prosecuted for what
they did
oh so that is what so nuts brings me to
my next question for you now a lot some
people are speculating that that's
exactly why the CIA is doing this
blowing the whistle right now at this
moment because they are launching an
investigation into actually how Russia
Gate got started who gave false
information you know they the guy who
started this whole thing was Mills food
if that's how you pronounce his name he
started the whole thing and it looks
like he was CIA right and he lied to the
FBI Muller admits in his report he lied
to the FBI three times they never
prosecuted him never reinter viewed him
so now they're gonna do a real now it
looks like they're gonna do a real
investigation into Russia gate and this
is to try to throw the dogs off the
scent or to try to distract everybody
from that and
engagin what do you say to that oh yeah
you know I think that the fix was in
with with Mifsud because you remember
when the hit the fan
they said well we can't find and he's a
very shadow he carried him on my show
University in the UK just pick up the
phone and call him
shadowy character they can't find him I
freaking found him yeah they could I
know wheat they they found him he was in
Tora Bora they let him go anyway so that
I think that this is what people aren't
this is what do you get amazed when you
watch the corporate media the MSNBC the
CNN's
you know I don't do you get amazed when
you watch their coverage ABC the whole
deal is crazy right yes you know I used
to watch Morning Joe every day not
because I like Joe Scarborough and Mika
Brzezinski but because they talked more
about politics than any of the other
morning shows and I just love politics
I've been a political animal all my life
well I I can't even watch that anymore
in the morning no now in all honesty I'm
not saying this to be funny I watch
reruns of adam-12
in the morning when I'm getting ready
for work because can't trust any of
these morning shows on any of the
network's
so I you know I I live on the west coast
so Morning Joe comes on here like 3:00
in the morning and so I used to watch it
a little night I used to watch it right
before I go to bed you watch it when you
get up i watch it right before I go to
bed because I like to go to bed angry
with a straight face and looking right
into the camera and saying Russia Russia
Russia what about Russia come on man hey
these people are that stupid they do and
do don't you remember though when Russia
hacked into our health care system and
denied 30 million people access don't
you remember when they did that don't
you remember when Russia hacked into our
banking system and foreclosed on 5.1
million families and kicked them out of
their houses and then gave those houses
back to those same bankers to sell them
back to don't you remember when Russia
did that don't remember in Russia made
80% of the workers live paycheck to
paycheck you got to get onto the
newsman I mean it's all Russia see I'm
watching the wrong networks yeah yeah
everybody we're doing a live show every
Sunday in October in Hollywood
California at the Sycamore tavern go to
jimmy dore comedy calm for a link for
tickets and become a patron we give you
hours of bonus material every month
become a Premium Member go to jimmy dore
comedy comm and sign up thanks for your
support
[Music]